<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>1. Introduction on FortiGate auto-scale and AWS GWLB</title>
    <link>https://fortilatam.github.io/index.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in 1. Introduction on FortiGate auto-scale and AWS GWLB</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://fortilatam.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>1. Pre-requisites</title>
      <link>https://fortilatam.github.io/prereq.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fortilatam.github.io/prereq.html</guid>
      <description>In this section we will step through the what is needed before you can get the most out of the rest of the walkthrough demo!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2. Hands-on</title>
      <link>https://fortilatam.github.io/demohandson.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fortilatam.github.io/demohandson.html</guid>
      <description>Remembering AWS diagram: In this demo, all these components are already setup.
We have:
FortiGate VM in two auto-scale groups: ASG FFlex (fgt_byol_asg: using FortiFlex licenses) and ASG PAYG (fgt_on_demand_asg: using PAYG FortiGate VMs) Routing is configured for 2 AZs (availability zones) but we will use only us-east-1a There are EC2 instances in every subnet that you will use The VPC Pub-testing-vpc is not connected with the other VPCs. You will use the EC2 hosted there to run attacks.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3. Tasks</title>
      <link>https://fortilatam.github.io/tasks.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fortilatam.github.io/tasks.html</guid>
      <description>These tasks were thinking of to demo some features of using FortiGate with gateway load balancer, but you can think in other tests.
Feel free to explore the AWS routing tables, check TGW configuration, etc. If you have suggestions for other labs, that are not here or you don&amp;rsquo;t have permission to do it, please write a comment in the same Sharepoint page you got the credentials.
There is no specific order to perform the tasks.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>4. Clean up</title>
      <link>https://fortilatam.github.io/cleanup.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fortilatam.github.io/cleanup.html</guid>
      <description>I hope this walkthrough demo helped you in someway.
We are all responsible for saving money for the company, so please, before you go stop all the EC2 and set FortiGate ASG to 0.
Stopping EC2 Open AWS Console Go to EC2 &amp;gt; Instances Check all the Instances and in &amp;ldquo;instance state&amp;rdquo; click &amp;ldquo;Stop instance&amp;rdquo; FortiGate ASG to 0 If you only stop the FortiGate instance the auto scaling group will start a new instance, so you need to change it as well In EC2 &amp;gt; scroll down to &amp;ldquo;Auto Scaling Groups&amp;rdquo; menu Select &amp;ldquo;fgt_byol_asg&amp;rdquo; and click &amp;ldquo;Edit&amp;rdquo; Set &amp;ldquo;Desired capacity&amp;rdquo; to 0 and click &amp;ldquo;Update&amp;rdquo; Now you are good to go!</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>