<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>3. Tasks on FortiGate auto-scale and AWS GWLB</title>
    <link>https://fortilatam.github.io/tasks.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in 3. Tasks on FortiGate auto-scale and AWS GWLB</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://fortilatam.github.io/tasks/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>3.1 Connectivity: North-South</title>
      <link>https://fortilatam.github.io/tasks/41_connectivityns.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fortilatam.github.io/tasks/41_connectivityns.html</guid>
      <description>When using FortiGate with GWLB you can save money and not using NAT Gateways. NAT GW&amp;rsquo;s are charge for hour and usage, with the scenario you have here, the FortiGate can be your NAT Gateway for all the VPCs connected.
NAT Gateways are used by private instances, what I mean is, the instances that don&amp;rsquo;t have public IPs. Instances that have public IP use IGW (Internet Gateway) to go to internet.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3.2 Connectivity: East-West</title>
      <link>https://fortilatam.github.io/tasks/42_connectivityew.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fortilatam.github.io/tasks/42_connectivityew.html</guid>
      <description>With the same FortiGate cluster, you can inspect the traffic between VPCs and subnets inside the same VPC.
In this task you will test both scenarios.
Traffic inspection between VPCs In AWS console, go to EC2 menu and click on &amp;ldquo;Instances&amp;rdquo;
Click &amp;ldquo;wk-spk1-pub-a&amp;rdquo; and then click &amp;ldquo;Connect&amp;rdquo; Click &amp;ldquo;EC2 serial console&amp;rdquo; and then &amp;ldquo;Connect&amp;rdquo; The login information is: user: student password: F0rt1n3t
Leave this console tab opened. Repeat the same process with the instance &amp;ldquo;wk-spk2-pub-a&amp;rdquo;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3.3 IPS: Log4Shell attack</title>
      <link>https://fortilatam.github.io/tasks/43_log4shellattack.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fortilatam.github.io/tasks/43_log4shellattack.html</guid>
      <description>Log4Shell is a zero-day vulnerability with a CVSS severity rating of 10 and it was largely explored few years ago&amp;hellip; and continues to these days. In this lab you will perform some attacks and block it using FGT.
The first thing we need to do is to start a Docker container with the vulnerable application
In AWS console, go to EC2 menu and click on &amp;ldquo;Instances&amp;rdquo;
Click &amp;ldquo;wk-spk1-pub-a&amp;rdquo; and then click &amp;ldquo;Connect&amp;rdquo; Click &amp;ldquo;EC2 serial console&amp;rdquo; and then &amp;ldquo;Connect&amp;rdquo; The login information is:</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>